DAYS!
I have only five years left.
（政(せい)）
俺に残された猶予は ５年しかない
In five more years, I will be 22.
５年たてば 俺は22になる
（信(しん)）えっ？
（貂(てん)）あっ ひょっとして…
Do you mean...
ああ 加冠の儀だ
Yes. The Crowning Ceremony.
加冠の儀を行えば 俺は
国内外に秦国(しんこく)君主として認知される
After the Crowning Ceremony is performed,
I will be recognized within the kingdom and without as the ruler of the State of Qin.
そうなれば―
When that happens, it is likely that some from the Lü Shi faction may drift over to my side.
呂氏(りょし)派の中から こちらに
流れてくる者が出てくるだろう
（信）５年で十分だ
Five years is plenty!
Xin?!
（貂）信…
We're not playing around here.
これは遊びじゃねえんだ
If the other side is going to decide things in five years, then that'll mean victory or defeat!
向こうが
５年で決めに来るっつうなら―
そこが勝負だ
That is right.
そういうことだ
Now then, Xin, how are you faring?
では 信 お前のほうは どうだ？
Can you become a full general in five years?
５年で将軍になれるか？
５年で 将軍に…
Become a full general... in five years?
The first general to be sent into battle by my order will be you, Xin.
俺の最初の号令で出陣する将軍は
お前だ 信
Five more years...
あと５年…
Even if Lü Buwei does come to crush us then,
たとえ 呂不韋(りょふい)がつぶしに来ようと
Zheng will become recognized as the true king of the State of Qin, no questions asked.
政は 秦国王として 文句なく
認められるようになるはずだ
So...
だから…
let's do it, Zheng!
やるぞ 政
俺も絶対 ５年で将軍になってやる
I'll become a full general in five years, no matter what it takes!
Kings and Ants
（魏兵(ぎへい)）あっ…
（どよめき）
ひ… 飛信(ひしん)隊だ！
It-It's the Feixin Unit!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）秦趙(しんちょう)同盟の成立以降
信が戻った飛信隊は―
After the Qin-Zhao Alliance was established and Xin returned to the Feixin Unit,
they wreaked more havoc on the front lines than ever before.
以前にも増して
前線で猛威を振るっていた
（斬る音）
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
（竜川(りゅうせん)）ン～ッ…
（殴る音）
（魏兵たち）ウワーッ！
（崇原(すうげん)）ハッ…
松左(しょうさ)！
（松左）えっ？
Song Zuo!
（魏兵）ウワッ！
So it's you guys, eh?
（剛炭(ごうたん)）お前らか　最近 この辺で
図に乗ってるという部隊は
The unit that's been acting all high and mighty around here recently.
H-He's huge!
（尾平(びへい)）で… でかい
（去亥(きょがい)）竜川より でかいぞ
He's even bigger than Long Chuan!
Whoever's the captain, get out front.
隊長は 前に出ろ
この剛炭さまが
三個錘(さんこすい)で 頭吹っ飛ばしてくれる
I, Gang Tan, will knock his head off with my triple-weight!
I don't have time to waste on you.
てめえなんかに
かまってる暇はねえ
こっちには５年しかねえんだ
I've only got five years.
R-Retreat!
（魏兵）ひ… ひけ！ ひけ！
Retreat!
Man, we've had a bunch of victories in a row!
（尾平）いやぁ
連戦連勝だな
もはや前線に敵なし　飛信隊 最強
It's like we're unrivaled on the front lines!
The Feixin Unit is the strongest!
（田永(でんえい)）なに調子乗ってんだ？
大して活躍もしてねえのに
Hey, don't get cocky now.
We haven't done anything that big.
相変わらず 口だけは達者だな
As usual, the only thing you're really good at is talking.
Shut up!
うるせえ！ いいじゃねえか
What's wrong with being a little happy after a victory?!
勝ち戦のあとぐらい
ちょっと浮かれたって
Yeah, he's right. Let him have his fun.
まあ そうだな　大目に見てやろう
I mean, with Wei Ping, we don't know if he'll be alive tomorrow.
尾平の場合 あしたは
生きてるか分かんねえんだし
Hold it, you!
待て こら！
There's no way in hell I'm gonna die!
俺は絶対 死なねえぞ
生きて帰って そんでもって―
I'm gonna return home alive and get fawned over by Dong Mei again!
また
東美(とうび)ちゃんに甘えるんだから～ん
（笑い声）
と… 東美ちゃん！ ウ～ン！
Oh, Dong Mei!
（壁(へき)）勝利した隊長の顔ではないな
（信）ハッ…
Now that's not the face of a victorious captain.
It's been quite a while, hasn't it, Xin?
（壁）久しぶりだな 信
Bi!
壁！
I was really surprised to hear the Feixin Unit had gotten this famous at the front lines.
（壁）しかし 驚いたぞ
前線で飛信隊が これほど有名とは
聞けば すぐに ここだと分かった
I found out you were here pretty fast.
That's because the front lines are small.
小さい前線だからな
ちょっとしたことで名は広まるんだ
Our name is spreading on small accomplishments.
But none of this is a big deal whatsoever.
でも
こんなの全然 大したこたぁない
フッ… 思ったとおり
相当 焦ってるみたいだな
Just as I expected, looks like you're really in a rush.
やはり
わざわざ会いに来た甲斐(かい)があった
It seems it was worth coming out here to see you.
えっ？
そういや なんで こんな所に壁が？
Oh yeah. What're you doing here, Bi?
亜水(あすい)城に 使いに行く途中だ
（信）えっ？
I'm on an errand to Yashui Castle.
信…
Xin, the effects of the Qin-Zhao Alliance are already becoming evident.
早くも 秦趙同盟のもたらす効果が
表に表れようとしている
Our war to capture Wei.
（壁）魏国への攻略戦だ
趙への警戒が無用になったため―
Because we're no longer being vigilant towards Zhao, we can now fully concentrate our forces on Wei.
本格的に
軍力を魏へ集中できるようになった
それを受けて
この度 魏の山陽(さんよう)に進軍し
On that note, we are going to advance troops into Shanyang in Wei,
周囲一帯に ひしめく20の城を
一気に奪い取る大戦略が―
in a grand plan of attack from Xiangyang to capture the cluster of 20 castles in that area in one fell swoop.
咸陽(かんよう)で打ち上げられたのだ
アッ… アア…
そ… そんな でけえ戦が…
A-A huge war like that is...
This is still top-secret information,
（壁）
このことは まだ極秘事項だが
but Xin, I decided to come here and tell it to you.
信 私は
あえて お前に伝えに来たのだ
えっ？
（壁）上の地位に駆け上がるには
The best way to ascend to higher ranks
こういう大戦で
大功を上げるのが いちばんだが
is to render major achievements in battles like this.
そのためには あらかじめ軍の中で
Although, before the fighting starts, it's necessary to be
stationed at a primary location amongst the army.
重要な所に
配置されておく必要がある
Why?
なんでだ？
戦場の端の
後方支援などに回されたら―
If we get shoved into rearguard support or something, there'd be no way for us to gain any military achievements.
武功など上げられないだろう
（尾平）なるほど
Ah, I get it.
So Xin, this isn't the time to be rotten.
だから 信
今は くさっている場合ではない
It's likely that the war to capture Wei will begin in less than a year.
魏国攻略戦が始まるまで
恐らく１年とない
So before then, build up as many achievements as you can, even if they're small ones
それまでに
小さな武功でも 確実に積み重ねて
少しでも
いい配置で本戦に臨むんだ
and get in the best location you can for when the main war starts!
ンッ…
（壁）だが この情報は―
However, this information has already leaked to prominent military commanders.
有力な武将たちには
既に 漏れ伝わっている
その証拠に
今言ったことを実戦するため―
As proof of that, in order to actually go about doing what I've been saying,
野望ある者たちが
この前線に集まってきている
ambitious people have been gathering at this front line.
Of course.
当然だな　上を目指すヤツは
俺たちだけじゃねえ
We're not the only ones with our eyes on the upper ranks.
けど そんなヤツらに負けるかよ！
But... there's no way in hell we'll lose to those guys!
Give it your all, Xin.
頑張れよ 信
Thanks for coming all the way out here to tell me.
わざわざ
伝えに来てくれて ありがとうな
I can always count on you, Brother Bi.
ホント 頼りになるよ
壁のあんちゃん
礼はいい　お前は目の離せない
弟のようなものだからな
No need to thank me.
You're like a little brother I can never take my eyes off of.
Check up on the units that have gathered around this area, would you?
この辺りに集まっている
部隊について 調べておいてくれ
How big they are, their achievements, anything you can find.
規模や戦績 何でもかまわん
（従者）はっ！
Yes, sir.
I may be meddling a bit too much...
少々 おせっかいかもしれんがな
And a few days later, a rare large fight occurred at the front line where Xin and his unit were.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
そして数日後　信たちのいる前線で
珍しく 大きな戦が起こっていた
In order to push the line back,
Qin
Wei
前線を押し返すべく
魏国軍が 周辺より集結し
the State of Wei gathered all of its troops in the area forming a large army of over 10,000.
１万を超える大軍と化したのである
これに対し 秦国軍は―
Against this, the State of Qin Army brought together units from the North and the South
北と南で 部隊を集結し
魏国軍を挟み撃つ作戦を立てた
planning to assault the Wei Army with a pincer attack.
This became the first mid-sized battle of the war.
この辺りでは初めての
中規模の戦となったのである
It's starting, Captain.
（石(せき)）
始まったぞ 隊長　両軍 約１万
Both armies have approximately 10,000.
これを逃(のが)す手はねえな 信
（信）ああ
There's no way they can get out of this, is there, Xin?
Yeah.
We, the Feixin Unit, will be independent reserve corps again.
俺たち飛信隊は 今回も独立遊軍だ
合戦中 自由に動けるが
ほかの助けはアテにできねえ
We'll be able to move freely once the armies clash, but we can't count on help from others.
We'll look for a good opportunity to act, and then take down the enemy general with our own strength!
好機を見極めて
俺たちの力だけで 大将を討つ
Right!
（田永）おう
Qiang Lei, let me know your opinion on this.
（信）
羌瘣(きょうかい) お前の意見を聞かせてくれ
With the State of Qin's power, we will probably reach a stalemate at the front of the enemy's headquarters.
（羌瘣）秦国軍の力では
敵本陣の手前で膠着(こうちゃく)するだろう
If our target is the enemy general...
敵将を狙うなら―
We should start at the back of our army, then cut around to the back of the enemy's headquarters.
まず 後ろについて
本陣の背に回り込んで突入する
Of course, it will be no easy task to break through the headquarters' defenses.
もちろん本陣の守備を突き破るのは
容易ではないがな
Mr. Yuan, Old Man Lü Yan?
渕(えん)さん 魯延(ろえん)じいは？
No objections.
（渕）異論なし
（魯延）同じく
Same.
よし やるぞ！
Okay, let's do it!
Push, push!
（隊長）押せ押せ！ 押し込め！
Push them back!
I-It's no good.
（兵士）ダ… ダメです
魏軍本陣まで届きません
We won't reach the State of Wei headquarters!
On the contrary, our soldiers are slowly being whittled away!
逆に こちらの兵が削られてます
このままでは…
At this rate...
（鬨(とき)の声）
オッ…
（兵士）あの部隊は何だ？
What unit is that?!
They crossed the enemy's defensive camp and are attacking the back of their headquarters!
防御陣をかわして
敵本陣の背に回り込むぞ
T-That's...
あ… あれは…
飛信隊だ！
The Feixin Unit!
Blast through in one push!
一気に突破するぞ！
Wh-Who are these guys?!
（魏兵）な… 何だ こいつら！
Th-They're strong!
（魏兵）つ… 強い！
（隊長）
ええい 何をしている！ 抜かせるな
What are you doing?! Don't let them through!
If they get past us, the headquarters will be completely exposed!
ここを抜かれては
もう本陣は丸裸… ハッ！
（斬る音）
（隊長）ウワッ！
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
Let's go!
（信）行くぞ
We're going to take that enemy general's head!
絶対 敵将を取る！
Xin
Huh?!
（陽(よう)）ええっ？
You still haven't done anything with his majesty?!
（陽）まだ
大王さまと な～んにもないの？
N-No...
（向(こう)）あっ… うん
I go to his bedroom,
ご寝所へ行っても いつも“黙って
隣にいるだけでいい”って言われて
but he always just says, "Just sitting next to me quietly is fine."
で… でも 向ちゃん もう何回も
大王さまに呼ばれてるでしょう
B-But Xiang, his majesty has called for you several times now, hasn't he?
He has never called for anyone more than once before.
ほかの人は大抵 １回きりなのに
う～ん…
（向）な… なに？
W-What?
う～ん… 何か特別なものが
あるようには見えないし…
I don't really see anything special about you.
Why are you the only one?
なんで向ちゃんだけなの？
（向）し…
I-I don't know!
知らないよ！
逃げるところが ますます怪しい
Running away like that makes her all the more suspicious.
待って 向ちゃん！
Wait up, Xiang!
もっと よく見せてよ！
Lemme get a better look!
Stop it, Yang!
やめて 陽ちゃん！ 知らないってば
Just hold on!
The State of Wei has attacked near the nation's border, again?
（政）国境付近で
また 魏国が侵攻してきたか
Yes, my king.
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）はっ…
Skirmishes continue day after day at the front lines, as usual.
相変わらず 前線では
連日 小競り合いが続いております
We must hasten our war to capture the State of Wei.
（政）
魏国への攻略戦 急がねばならぬな
Five years?
５年か…
Huh?
Hurry and climb your way up here.
早く上ってこい　待っているぞ
I'm waiting for you, Xin!
信…
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
（信）オリャー！
Go, go!
行け行け！ 隊長に後れを取るな！
Don't fall behind the captain!
（尾平･昂(こう)）あっ！
All right!
しゃ！ 抜けた！ 敵将を取れー！
We made it through!
Let's take the general's head!
アッ… アア… 何だ？ これは
What... is this?
T-They're all dead.
（渕）ぜ… 全員 討たれている
（尾平）本陣が… 壊滅してる
The headquarters... has been destroyed?
Wh-What's going on here?
ど… どういうこった？
What's that?!
何だ？ 誰かいる
Someone's there!
Oh? This is a surprise.
（王賁(おうほん)）ほう… 驚いたな
Someone else targeted the headquarters?
我々のほかにも
本陣を狙う者がいたとは
しかし 残念だが ひと足遅かったな
You're a tad bit too late, I'm afraid.
俺らより先に 敵将を討っただと？
This guy killed the enemy general before I could?!
Who is this guy?
（信）何者(なにもん)だ？ この男は
A-A mounted unit?
き… 騎馬隊か
（番陽(ばんよう)）そこの歩兵ども！
Foot soldiers over there!
Whom is your unit affiliated with?!
（番陽）どこの所属の部隊か？
We are affiliated with the State of Qin's Northern Army.
わ… 我々は 秦国北軍所属
特殊三百人隊の飛信隊
The special 300-man unit, the Feixin Unit!
そちらは いずこの？
With whom are you affiliated?
なに？
What?!
（兵士）飛信隊…
Feixin Unit?
Did he say Feixin Unit?
Wh-Which unit are you?!
そ… そちらは いずこの部隊か？
What's wrong? You guys identify yourselves, too.
どうした？ そっちも名乗りやがれ
我々は玉鳳(ぎょくほう)隊
秦国南軍所属の特殊三百人隊だ
We are the Yufeng Unit.
Special 300-man unit of the State of Qin's Southern Army.
Yufeng Unit
と… 特殊三百人隊って…
（去亥）お… 俺たちと同じ
S-Special 300-man unit?!
Th-The same as us?!
I see.
そうか　諸君らが あの飛信隊
So you gentlemen are the Feixin Unit...
What're you laughing at, you bastards?!
なに笑ってやがんだ てめえら！
（王賁）
フッ… すまない 非礼を許せ
Excuse me. Forgive our rudeness.
しかし これには訳がある
But there is a reason for this.
The Feixin Unit, a group whose name we have heard profusely as of late...
最近 やたらと耳にする飛信隊
As another 300-man unit, we have honestly been keeping a vigilant eye out for you.
同じ特殊三百人隊として 正直
その存在を警戒していたのだが
But we never thought you were a group of peasant soldiers like the rumors said.
まさか ウワサどおりに―
農民歩兵の集まりとは
思ってもみなかった
We were all so surprised that we doubted our own eyes.
みな目を疑うほど驚いた次第だ
Please forgive us.
許せ
（笑い声）
（田有(でんゆう)･竜川）ンンッ…
Quit laughing!
笑うな！
Is there something wrong with being peasant soldiers?!
農民歩兵で悪いのかよ？
結局 同じ三百人隊だろうが！
We're both 300-man units, ain't we?!
We are not the same, you fool.
同じなわけがないであろうが
バカ者
What?!
なに？
We, the Yufeng Unit,
（王賁）我々 玉鳳隊は―
貴士族の中でも 幼少期より
軍事教育を施された英才集団だ
are a gifted group among noble and warrior families, that was trained from early childhood in the military arts.
Before peasant children were even picking up hoes,
農民の子が 鍬(くわ)を持つより早く
我々は剣を持ち 槍(やり)を振るい
we were holding swords, swinging spears,
個人 集団戦術を
たたき込まれている
and being taught individual and group tactics.
On the other hand, you gentleman are amateurs at war whose principal occupation is farm work.
一方 諸君らは
本職を農耕とする戦の素人
たまたま 武功を立て続けに上げて
喜んでいるのは分かるが
We understand your joy in your occasional successive rendering of achievements,
我々と同列と思われては不愉快だ
but I find it disconcerting for you to consider yourselves to be of the same rank as us.
It is a big mistake for a group of ordinary foot soldiers such as yourselves
そもそも 一般歩兵の君たちが―
特殊部隊をやっていること自体
大きな間違いなのだ
to be acting as a special unit in the first place.
On the battlefield, your proper existential value
戦場において
君たちの正しい存在価値は―
is that of ants.
蟻(あり)であることだぞ
（信）ンンッ…
（尾平）蟻？
Ants?
（王賁）私情を挟むことなく
上の命令を忠実に実践する働き蟻
Worker ants without personal feelings,
who merely faithfully carry out orders given to them from those above them.
Your most important duty as foot soldiers is to devote yourselves to that.
これに徹することが
君たち歩兵の最も重要な責務だ
Of course, we are not making light of you.
もちろん
君たちを軽んじているわけではない
When a large army of over 10,000 is formed,
10万を超える大軍を作るとき
８割は 君たち一般歩兵だ
80% of that is comprised of you foot soldiers.
軍の基礎力は君たちであり
その存在なしに戦はできない
You are the foundation of an army.
Without that, there is no war.
However, ants are ants.
ただし 蟻は蟻
Leave advanced positions, like
independent reserve units, to us.
独立遊軍など高度なことは
我らに任せて―
You should focus all of your strength on your natural post.
君たちは本来の持ち場で力を尽くせ
分をわきまえぬ夢を見ると
不幸になるぞ
To get caught up in dreams and not know one's place will only cause disaster.
Well, I can imagine which idiot instigated this.
まあ どこのバカが たきつけたかは
想像がつくがな
As we thought.
（壁）やはりな
There are many small units gathering there from all over, trying to gain recognition before the war starts.
魏国への攻略戦までに
名を上げようと―
各地から
かなりの小隊が集まっている
And among them is the Yufeng Unit.
中でも玉鳳隊
This 300-man unit is already outstanding.
この三百人隊は
既に ぬきんでている
しかも その隊長は…
Plus, their captain is...
Don't lose to them, Xin.
負けるなよ 信
We should get going soon.
そろそろ まいりましょう
敵将の首を掲げて戦を終わらせねば
We must raise the enemy general's head and put an end to this battle.
Right.
Hold it right there!
（信）待ちやがれ！
L-Lord Xin, please calm down!
し… 信どの 冷静に
相手は 恐らく貴士族の…
That man is most likely from a noble...
うるせえ！
Shut up!
何なんだよ？
Even after patiently listening to that whole thing, I don't get your problem!
さっきから
黙って聞いてりゃ てめえは
貴族か士族か知んねえが
I don't know a thing about noble or warrior families,
but once a war starts, that shit doesn't matter one bit, you moron!
戦が始まりゃ
そんなもん関係ねえんだ バカが！
With these hands of ours, we've beat the shit outta arrogant bastards just like you!
俺たちは この手で―
てめえらみてえに偉ぶったヤツらを
ぶっ倒してきたぜ
Which of us is a moron?
バカは どっちだ？ 蟻の話が
理解できておらんではないか
Did you not understand my speech about ants?
Vice Captain Pan Yang.
番陽副長
（番陽）はっ…
Yes, sir.
Wh-What's going on?
な… 何だ？
All soldiers, at attention!
全員 気をつけ！
（沛浪(はいろう)）チッ…
フン… フハハハッ！
There you have it!
そういうことだ
少しは理解できたか？
Do you understand a bit better now?
野郎！
（松左）やめとけ
Bastard!
Don't.
That's all I can bear.
（信）我慢の限界だ
Old man, get down from that horse right now and apologize.
おっさん
今すぐ馬から下りて わび入れろ
If you don't, I'll drag you down by force.
さもなきゃ力ずくで引きずり下ろす
Oh? With that toy sword of yours?
ほう… その おもちゃの剣でか？
Y-You bastard!
（信）てめえ！
Lord Xin!
信どの！
By the way, let me offer some candid advice to you, personally, as well.
ついでに
苦言を君本人にも言っておきたい
I understand that you rose from being a servant and you yell about becoming a full general.
なんでも 君は下僕の出で しかも
将軍になると うそぶいているとか
ンッ…
（王賁）いま貴士族から―
Right now, military commanders who are talented and young like me, are emerging from noble or warrior families.
俺のような若く才能ある武将たちが
台頭してきている
The competition for the seat of the next full general is already underway.
次の将軍の座を狙った競争が
既に始まっているのだが
But there is not a bit of room
for a roadside weed like you.
路傍の雑草のごとき君が そこに
入り込む余地など 微塵(みじん)もないぞ
At best, the highest you will get is 1000-man general.
君は よくて千人将止まりだ
X-Xin...
し… 信…
No, it's a reverse thrust.
いや 逆突きだ
Lord Xin!
（渕）信どの！
（尾平）信！
Xin!
T-There is no need to use longzhi on someone like that.
な… なにも あのような者に
“龍指(りゅうし)”など使わずとも
Longzhi?
（松左）龍指？
That stabbing technique with an ever-changing trajectory, like that of a dragon?
龍のごとく
変幻自在の軌道を描く突き技か
This man... is strong.
この男 強い…
Honestly, you were always an eyesore.
（王賁）正直 ずっと目障りだった
So there is a need for me to make it clear for you while I have the chance.
今のうちに
きっちり示しておく必要がある
The decisive difference between you and I!
俺と お前の決定的な差を
（信）ウウッ… て… てめえ
Y-You bastard...
（王賁）飛信隊隊長 覚えておけ
Feixin Unit captain, remember this.
My name is Wang Ben.
我が名は王賁
Wang Ben?
王賁？
Wang...
“王”…
“王”！
Wang?!
Yes.
ああ
お前の大好きな あの王騎(おうき)の一族
The same family as your beloved Wang Qi.
Unlike Wang Qi, who was of a branch family,
分家の王騎とは違い
I, Wang Ben, have inherited the blood of the main Wang family.
王一族の総本家を継ぐ王賁だ
Wang Ben
State of Qin Special 300-Man Unit
Yufeng Unit 300-Man General
We will be staying at the front for a little while.
我らは
しばらく この前線に とどまる
この先
武功は上げられぬと覚悟しておけ
Be prepared to not render any more achievements.
Preview
A Third Force
End